Rob Christopher Atalla

Kansas City Missouri, 64114 | 816.507.5957 <u>linkedin.com/in/ratalla816 | ratalla816.github.io/professional-portfoliorob.atalla@gmail.com</u>

CAREER SUMMARY

Driven and tech-savvy inventory management professional with a relentless passion for efficiency and accuracy. Known for being teachable, personable, proactive, and facilitative, as well as a strong business acumen developed during almost a decade of logistics and P&L experience. Familiar with various inventory management technologies, regex and search strings, also received formal training in database development and management from the University of Kansas

WORK EXPERIENCE

PROBLEM SOLVER II / IOL / ICQA

Amazon | New Century, KS December 2021 - Present

- Troubleshoot and resolve edge case customer returns; includes updating item dispositions, repairing broken SKU's, moving inventory to proper container numbers, and using alternative methods to locate order numbers when an RMA is not available.
- Research inventory in odd locations to reconcile physical and virtual quantities and delete virtual quantities if inventory cannot be physically located.
- Inspects processed return items for quality issues, and updates resale conditions if necessary.
- Collaborates with managers and warehouse associates in multiple departments to manage efficiency, quality, and safety.
- Coaches associates on quality defects by issuing Mastermind tickets and performing sorter audits.
- Submit IOL reports and ICQA audits daily.

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

Western Logistics Express | North Kansas City, MO April 2021 - September 2021

- Created relationships within client organizations through cold calling, network lead prospecting, and email campaigns.
- Analyzed market data and trends to develop customer pricing strategies.
- Sourced and managed vendors.
- Served as sales coach and accountability partner for new hires.
- Left in September 2021 to complete full stack web development program.

SENIOR ACCOUNT EXECUTIVE

Freightquote / C.H. Robinson | Kansas City, MO May 2014 - April 2021

- Seized single-source opportunities by leveraging proprietary Enterprise SaaS solutions.
- Responsible for sourcing and developing multiple division top-ten accounts.
- Demonstrated ability to negotiate resources and priorities with multiple stakeholders to drive business results.
- Conducted quarterly business reviews with all clients in portfolio.
- Managed day-to-day customer commitments and maintained service levels through use of metrics and analytics.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

MongoDB, MongoDB Atlas, Mongoose Webpack, React JS, GraphQL

Node.js, Express.js **RESTful APIs** SQL, Sequelize

ORM, MVC, PWA, MERN

lest, Insomnia, Inquirer

CompTIA A+

Amazon AWS S3 / DynamoDB

SOFT SKILLS

Organized and diligent Contract negotiation Project management

Solution / Enterprise-level sales

Context switching Presentation delivery

Vendor management Pricing analysis

DATABASE TECHNICAL **PROJECTS**

FORGE | September 2021

GitHub: github.com/ratalla816/Forge Deployment: forge-team.herokuapp.com

ECOMMERCE BACK END | September 2021

GitHub: github.com/ratalla816/ecommerce-back-end

Not deployed - Back end only

MVC TECH BLOG | October 2021

GitHub: github.com/ratalla816/mvc-tech-blog

Deployment: robs-tech-talk-emporium.herokuapp.com

BUDGET TRACKER | October 2021

GitHub: github.com/ratalla816/budget-tracker

Deployment: ratalla816-budget-tracker.herokuapp.com

BRO BOOK | October 2021

GitHub: github.com/ratalla816/bro-book Deployment: Not deployed - Back end only

CODE COMMAND | November 2022

GitHub: github.com/ratalla816/code-command Deployment: code-command-team.herokuapp.com

PYTHON NEWSFEED | Ianuary 2022

GitHub: github.com/ratalla816/python-newsfeed Deployment: robs-tech-emporium.herokuapp.com

EDUCATION

November 2021

CERTIFICATE - FULL STACK WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

The University of Kansas, Edwards Campus, Overland Park, Kansas

Expected June 2022

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

California Coast University, Santa Ana, California